<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau | Transponster</title>
    <link>/tags/tableau/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tableau</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2018 Kapil Khanal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/aph-salt-spring-zoom.jpg</url>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>/tags/tableau/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Dashboard for StockX Contest</title>
      <link>/post/stockx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/stockx/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;stockx-data-contest-2019&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stock&lt;span style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;X&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Data Contest 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;https://stockx.com/news/the-2019-data-contest/&#34;&gt;StockX Challenge&lt;/a&gt; is a call for data and sneakers nerds to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/stockX_files/sneaker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;source: stockX&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;source: stockX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is this: they give you a bunch of original StockX sneaker data, then you crunch the numbers and come up with the coolest, smartest, most compelling story you can tell. It can be literally anything you want. A theory, an insight, even just a really original data visualization. It could be a novel hypothesis about resale prices you’ve always wanted to test. Or maybe it’s just a beautiful chart to visualize the data. It can be on any subject – sneakers, brands, buyers, or even StockX itself. Whatever you find interesting, just follow your bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also gave a shot on trying to come up with something useful. Below is my finished data dashboard. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;my-data-dashboard-for-stockx&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Data Dashboard for Stock&lt;span style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;X&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/index_files/stockX.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Dashboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link for tableau worksheet is &lt;a href = &#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/StockX_0/Dashboard1?:embed=y&amp;:display_count=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calculations on the Dashboards&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Price ratio&lt;/code&gt;: Ratio of Sales to Retail Price for Each Sneakers &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Weeks&lt;/code&gt;: (Order Date - Release Date) Converted in Weeks.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Median Price ratio&lt;/code&gt; is chosen to eliminate the effect of asymmetrical range of dates(2017-2019 not
complete as 2018) and counts of sneakers sales.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Color&lt;/code&gt; Scale for two brands are consistent whenever there is plot relating to brands.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1) Order of Sneakers by brand for weeks from Release Date&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plot shows the total count of orders for different sneakers of two brands
Both Brands are ordered before the release date. Off white has more orders than yeezy on the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;its-interesting-how-the-demand-of-yeezy-increased-at-around-90-weeks-after-the-release-of-the-shoes.&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It’s interesting how the demand of yeezy increased at around &lt;code&gt;90 weeks&lt;/code&gt; after the release of the shoes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)&lt;b&gt;Ratio of Sales Price to Retail Price For each Brand by Weeks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plot look at the relation of ratio of sale price to retail price for each brands and weeks after release
date. Clearly,Both Brand’s sale price is more than the retail price. The ratio of off-White increases in
general regardless of the individual sneakers while the ratio of yeezy brands is somewhat noisy but it has
a trend like off white. Both brand’s price ratio is increased after the release date.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3)Distribution of Median Sales price given the retail price for each brand&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This plot looks in detail on how the median sale price is distributed for each sneaker. The distribution of
median sale price for top 28 sneakers which were sold as least as 5 times over retail price are plotted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4) Median Price and States&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plot is looking at the median price ratio for all the states. The color scale is chosen for the ratio and
the size of the sneakers shows total sales relative to others. Which states usually pays more for
sneakers? Clearly, Delaware,Vermont,Utah had some sales with high price ratio. States like California and
Newyork have a lot of sales as shown by their relative sizes. The relative size is calculated by taking the
log of total sales in each states. States like Wyoming have less Sales and also with lower sales ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winona Area Public Schools: Community Contribution</title>
      <link>/post/waps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/waps/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;winona-area-public-schools-data-visualization&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:purple&#34;&gt;Winona Area Public Schools Data Visualization &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Introduction&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
This Project addresses the need of communication of public school data to community members in an meaningful way.Also, making the data available to general public in a proper and useable format. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Primarily, this Project was focused on cleaning and visualizing the Enrollment,Expenditures and Staffing History reports of the Winona Area Public District(WAPS) available publicly through Minnesota department of education, Data Center
Link:&lt;a href=&#34;http://education.state.mn.us/MDE/Data/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://education.state.mn.us/MDE/Data/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/WAPS_files/waps.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;
Methods and Steps of Projects
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.
1)Data Inspection/Acquisition:.&lt;br&gt;
Data was made available by Allison Quam(Representative from WAPS District).
The Data were made available in different pdf/excel files. Also, the information were scattered in different files.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)Data Cleaning and Formatting&lt;br&gt;
First,most of the pdf files were converted to excel by Tabula(Link:&lt;a href=&#34;http://tabula.technology/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://tabula.technology/&lt;/a&gt;) and online tool(&lt;a href=&#34;http://pdftoexcel.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://pdftoexcel.com&lt;/a&gt;)
then, they were cleaned up in proper format and stacked using Python (Pandas).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3)Data Exploration and Visualization &lt;br&gt;
This part of the project is focused on addressing the questions provided by representative of WAPS(&lt;code&gt;Allison Quam&lt;/code&gt; ).
Tableau was used extensively to explore the data and visualize it.
Primarily, i focused on answering following questions.&lt;br&gt;
1. &lt;span style=&#34;color:purple&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was curious about,how does the enrollment and capture rate(rate of new born enrolling to Kindergarten)is changing on WAPS district?.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After few meetings with representative, i knew she was curious about how schools spends on across different programs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;span style=&#34;color:purple&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How the expenditure per average daily membership (count of student daily served in schools) and spending on various category is changing?.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;acknowledgement&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank Allison Quam and Prof.Silas Bergen on helping and guiding me to understand the terms and calculations already done in the reports and Prof.Todd Iverson to help figure out Python code for cleaning the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the tableau file and the data is &lt;a href = &#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/WinonaAreaPublicSchoolsDataStory/FourthDashboard?:retry=yes&amp;:embed=y&amp;:display_count=yes&amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Visual Story Begins….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/WAPS_files/Second_Dashboard.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/WAPS_files/Third_Dashboard.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/WAPS_files/Fourth_Dashboard.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
