<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Transponster</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2018 Kapil Khanal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/aph-salt-spring-zoom.jpg</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watershed Quality in Minnesota</title>
      <link>/post/lake_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lake_data/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Link of the Competition the data is of : &lt;a href=&#34;http://minneanalytics.org/minnemudac-2016/data/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://minneanalytics.org/minnemudac-2016/data/&lt;/a&gt;
Our Submission as a freshmen :
MINNEMUDAC:2016
Water Quality Analytics Competiton:
A blog on Data Analytics Competition that we recently participated . We were Ranked 5th out of 19th team that participated from regional universities of Midwest USA
This is the Analysis Report of a Analytics Competition that i participated in Minnesota on Nov 4 and Nov 5 in Eden Praire, Optum Technologies. This Competition was Organized by Minneanalytics[biggest analytics Group in Minneapolis], MUDAC[ Yearly analytics event of Winonat State University] and Social Data Science[a Data Science for Social Good Platform based in Minneapolis]
A Glimpse of the Event and our Report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet Smile After We Flopped our First Presentation[We gave five presentation.There were 88 judges and they were Water Expert, Data Scientists, Policy Makers]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction of my Wondeful Team Members:
Kapil Khanal
Freshmen
Data Science Major
Data entrepreneurship enthusiastic
Melek Hakim
Senior
Computer Science Major with Data Science Minor
Linh Leo Nguyen
Sophomore
Computer Science Major
Rene Stiller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior
Communication Arts and Literature Education Major with Math Education Minor
[The Savior of our Presentation.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Crunching Number with members of my Team at Midnight before the Presentation day. ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents
1. Overview
Importance of Water Quality
This year is called the Year of Water Action. Governor Mark Dayton[Governor of Minnesota,2016] has begun an initiative aimed at “urging businesses, the agricultural industry, outdoor enthusiasts, communities and families to take action to conserve and improve water quality.”
We are members of the Minnesota community and understand the importance of being informed about our state’s resources. Governor Dayton is dedicated to finding solutions for the conditions of the Minnesota lakes where at this time, 40% of Minnesota’s waters are considered to be polluted.
Problem Statement
To get a Understanding of how water lake Quality in Minnesota has been Performing. It is Also to understand how other Social data like property value, agriculture or Residents have Affected to water quality or vice versa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objective and Scope of the Project
Minnesota Water Quality and its impact in the Community. These Following Questions have been put Forwarded by the Minnesota Water Activists and Water Departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a)How does property value influence water quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b)What property characteristics influence water quality the most?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c)Have changes in land use or land development over time positively or adversely impacted water quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d)What lakes tend to have the best / worst water quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e)Are the lakes with the best / worst water quality consistent over time?
Data Sources
&lt;a href=&#34;http://minneanalytics.org/minnemudac/data/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://minneanalytics.org/minnemudac/data/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools and Techniques
Our Team Used Tableau, JMP and R for Data Cleaning, Data Exploration,Visualization and Model Development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Description and Preparation
Classification of variables of Data
A. Numerical
Phosphorus
Sechhi Depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Categorical
Grade[Primary Interests]
Physical Condition
Recreational Suitability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions: Property Data Set&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property ownership is an investment and the hope is that your investment will gain value over time. What locations have seen the most substantial increase / decrease in property values over time?
The type of dwelling or type of property owner (i.e. public, commercial, residual, etc.) may adversely impact water quality. What locations have seen the most change or growth in these characteristics over time?
Local and county governments are often responsible for developing policies and regulating land development. What locations have seen the most change in land development over time? What variations exist in how land is being developed across various local and county governments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions: Property Data Set&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property that is contiguous to a lake, i.e. lake front property, is likely to influence its value. What is the relationship between proximity to water and property value? What effect does location have on this relationship? Does time influence this relationship?
What relationships exist between various property characteristics (i.e. dwelling type, ownership type, etc.) and proximity to water? Have these relationships changed over time? Do the policies / regulations of local or county governments appear to influence these relationships?
Does proximity to water appear to influence how land is being developed over time? Does the amount of influence vary across local or county governments?
Data Quality
The data Was really huge for a 4GB memory Laptop. It was really a Messy Data, as we were expecting it to be. It was as Messy as the Water quality itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis
Corelation of Phosphorus and Sechhi Depth on other Categorical Data
Histogram &amp;amp; Box Plots
Histogram of
Scatterplot of Numerical Data
Seasonality Analysis of Categorical Variable
over the Time for Each Lake was Visualized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the Data was Prepared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data was prepared with the guidance of our faculty supervisors. Our Laptops obviously was unable to process the exorbitant size of the data. To solve this, we took out lake with insufficient data and null values and focused on the data that was sufficie and we asked our Supervisors to clean the data in their Powerful Computers of our department. Our area of focus was the parcels approximately 350 meters from the lake shore.We use Jmp to subset the data and make the Summary table of the data we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings
Evaluation metric:
Parameter of Success:
Lake Ranking, Causation of water Pollution
The Metric we used for Phosphorus level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was determined by the lakes’ high grades, high secci score, and low phosphorus levels. There was a strong correlation between levels of phosphorus and the grade and secci Scores.
Model Development:
We used Random Forest to model the data and sort the variable of Most importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Four Lakes
Worst Four Lakes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Carnelian Lake
Shields Lake
Square Lake
Kramer Lake
Jane lake
Bay Lake
Halfbred Lake
Swede lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the Ranking of Lakes Based on the Phosphorus level and a Snap shot of Our Best Performing Little Carnellion Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid fluctuation in Secchi depth is shown by the bar graph in last plot of above picture.
It Shows lakes are More Clearer right before Summer . They have Increased Transparency at that time but after Summer Exposure, they immediately become less Clearer.Our understanding of the Algal Growth is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a high error rate(?).This suggest why our box plot goes up immediately. So,it is natural to see a pattern of fluctuation in sechhi depth but we can see that the fluctuation sometimes becomes abnormal than expected. Sometimes there is sustained increase in the height of box plot as in above picture This means lake was Clear. Lets have a look at the above histograms and Bar graph. Whenever there is decrease in phosphorus level, there is increase in Height of secchi depth. This Suggest there must be Somekind of Corelationin phosphorus an d Secchi depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower the phosphorus level, the higher the grade. This is not a perfect correlation, but strong enough that we conclude that phosphorus is the main component to determine a body of water’s quality. Four of these top performing lakes are in the same watersheds, called the Lower St. Croix River Watershed. This leads us to believe that phosphorus and secci levels are consistent between the lakes in the watershed. indicating Eutrophication.This Makes Sense because phosphorus is the nutrient that most influences the growth of algae in lakes. Excess algae in lake water can cause a disturbance to the normal equilibrium of the aquatic ecosystem. As algae plants die and decompose, bacteria consume oxygen that is dissolved in the water. Increased algal growth can lead to a decline in oxygen levels, accelerating the decline of water quality/ declining water clarity, and decreasing transparency.
Here is a visualization of the water quality of lakes in Minneapolis, Minnesota. The Red spots and the orange Spots are the Spots to worry.
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elements of land use and land development that impact water quality
The value of a property adjacent to lakes, bays, and rivers reflects the overall quality of the water and area resources.Below is the Visualization of the Agricultural Preserve land nearby the lakes. Clearly ,we can see more land in sub urban area of Minneapolis are Preserved for Agriculture.And those are the Region where Eutrophication is Common and the lakes with Stimulated Plant Growth occurs.
Possible Hypothesis for this Causation is
Excessive amount of Fertilizers in Agricultural land or improper management of Runoff Water. Contrary to the common belief that lake quality being degraded by the residential area nearby it, we found that agricultural land is more Hazardious than Residential area.
And Everytime we Cross Checked the Location of Bad Lakes, we Always found a Golf Course Naerby to it.
Are Golf Course detrimental to health of lakes? Yes, we Found it is most Affecting man made structure that is affecting the lake quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount that people are willing to pay for the properties is shown in the market value of the houses and lands. As the quality of the water improves,it is expected that people will pay more to live by the clean, transparent lake but our analysis on data Revealed Something not obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Above Box plot Shows that the Median EMV is Approximately Same for both Eutrophic andn uncontaminated lake but the Lake with slighlty stimulated plant growth has higher EMV. So based on this , we Recommend customers to opt for home by Uncontaminated lake than by plant growth Stimulated.We Found that People are Paying high price even for the Contaminated lake than uncontaminated. They are paying most for the lake that are Stimulated for algal Growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the water quality mapped by EMV. This is a snapshot of the interactive dashboard in tableau showing the change in the EMV by lake by year. We even Categorized the lake by waterquality to see the change going on in each lake in each year.
Here is the Histogram Plot for the EMV. It Clearly Shows that our Average Priced Home will be Somewhere in that Spike in the Curve. It is 160k for a average price for a House in Minneapolis Metropolitan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Do Our Data Suggest us for a average priced house in a Average water quality lake?
This is the lake that has Above average water quality[Ranked 9th best Lake in our Evaluation metric] and below average price. So, We Suggest you to Consider these area if you are looking for a house that is relatively cheap and near a Good Lake. It is a new oppurtunity for Real Estate agencies to focus on these area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion and Recommendations
a)Limit the Golf Course area near to the Lakes.
b)Develop a policy to limit the use of fertiliser in Agriculture reserve. We need to immediately work on this issue than decreasing the residential area nearby to lake.
Lets not forget that we analyzed the vast trove of data of few Variables. The Analysis Could Have been Much More Accurate if we have had the Data on the number of different Species Found in the lake. So we Recommend the Water Department to build new infrastructures that measure temperature of water , Species in the lake, And Air pollution around the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my Wonderful team for collaboration and Professor for Helping this happen !
For interactive Dashboard of our Report:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/profile/malek.hakim#!/vizhome/PARCELS_Story/WaterQualityVisualizationsintheTwinCities&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://public.tableau.com/profile/malek.hakim#!/vizhome/PARCELS_Story/WaterQualityVisualizationsintheTwinCities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work Cited
Carpenter, S. R., Caraco, N. F., Correll, D. L., Howarth, R. W., Sharpley, A. N., &amp;amp; Smith, V. H. (1998). Nonpoint pollution of surface waters with phosphorus and nitrogen. Ecological applications, 8(3), 559-568.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office of the Governor and Lt. Governor. (2016, August). A Year of Water Action in Minnesota. Retrieved October 30, 2016, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mn.gov/governor/issues/wateraction/index.jsp&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://www.mn.gov/governor/issues/wateraction/index.jsp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RMBEL. (2015, May 11). Property values and lake water quality - RMBEL. Retrieved October 30, 2016, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmbel.info/property-values-and-lake-water-quality-2/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmbel.info/property-values-and-lake-water-quality-2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water Transparency - RMBEL. (n.d.). Retrieved October 30, 2016, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmbel.info/water-transparenc&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmbel.info/water-transparenc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
This project is divided into two parts.
&lt;li&gt;
Data Cleaning and Data Management&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Product and Presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Part of this project was done in Python. This is the link of the code:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/DSCI430/blob/master/project_data_khanal.py&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/DSCI430/blob/master/project_data_khanal.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Data was sponsored by MinneMUDAC as part of the Fall Data Challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the project was focused on the making a usable data product.
The link of the code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/DSCI430/blob/master/app.R&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/DSCI430/blob/master/app.R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Below you can use this product&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;1000&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;yes&#34;  src=&#34;https://kapilkhanal.shinyapps.io/r_final_app/&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police  Data Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/police-data-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/police-data-challenge/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Please visit here for code and data
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/Police-Data-Challenge&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/KapilKhanal/Police-Data-Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secretory Problem</title>
      <link>/post/secretoryproblem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/secretoryproblem/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;when-to-give-up-exploration-vs-exploitation&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;B&gt;When to give up? Exploration vs Exploitation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of hard working students don’t end up being selected for the scholarships. I should know because i lost 3 years doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now i turn into a information theoretic game to find when should i have quit the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assumption: Your best score will get you scholarship if you are one of the sufficiently prepared student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say, entrance exams are the games. We all agree they do behave as a game. If a student is well prepared as indicated by practice questions and exams, then getting their name in scholarship in list is basically a game of chance. This is not to say that it is not possible but given that we all have time and money constrains in our life, when is the right amount to quit. Thus, A player in this game is a sufficiently prepared, hard working student. for others, before playing this game one has to be efficiently prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we agree, getting your name on that list is a work of chance. Say, that you are prepared to give entrance exams 10 times but that will come at a cost of time and money. Out of 10 exams you give, say all these exams can be ranked from your best score to worst score , thus you can rank them from 1 to 10. We can agree on one thing that your best possible score has the highest chance of getting scholarship[which may not be necessarily true for all but our player is a smart, hardworking , well prepared one.].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we give exams one by one and the score one get is random after some cutoff[for me it was 90]. We can all relate to the “fact” that some questions are actually random and they determine our fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we don’t know which exam’s is gonna be the best score for us. so its ideal to assume that it is random. After we give each exams, we surely can rank which one was the best exams and which one was the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The optimal solution is to give n/e exams before deciding to quit and quit after the n/e exams if the score on n/e + 1 is not better than the exams before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;def quit_candidate(n):
    &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;Choose a exam to quit after.. from a list of n exam using 
    the optimal strategy. 1= best time to quit,n is worst time to quit&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;

    exams = np.arange(1, n+1)
    np.random.shuffle(exams)
    
    stop = int(round(n/np.e)) 
    best_from_rejected = np.min(exams[:stop])
    rest = exams[stop:]
    
    try:
        return rest[rest &amp;lt; best_from_rejected][0]
    except IndexError:
        return exams[-1]
#Now let&amp;#39;s see if it actually holds..by having  100,000 student give 100 exams

sim = np.array([quit_candidate(n=100) for i in range(100000)])

plt.figure(figsize=(10, 6))
plt.hist(sim, bins=100)
plt.xticks(np.arange(0, 101, 10))
plt.ylim(0, 40000)
plt.xlabel(&amp;#39;Chosen candidate&amp;#39;)
plt.ylabel(&amp;#39;frequency&amp;#39;)
plt.show()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://imrankhan17.github.io/pages/figs/secretary/fig1.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;img&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see most of the time we ended up quiting on the prime time[rank 1 is the prime time to quit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;best_candidate = []
for r in range(5, 101, 5):
    sim = np.array([quit_candidate(n=100, reject=r) for i in range(100000)])
    # np.histogram counts frequency of each candidate
    best_candidate.append(np.histogram(sim, bins=100)[0][0]/100000)

plt.figure(figsize=(10, 6))
plt.scatter(range(5, 101, 5), best_candidate)
plt.xlim(0, 100)
plt.xticks(np.arange(0, 101, 10))
plt.ylim(0, 0.4)
plt.xlabel(&amp;#39;% of candidates rejected&amp;#39;)
plt.ylabel(&amp;#39;Probability of choosing best candidate&amp;#39;)
plt.grid(True)
plt.axvline(100/np.e, ls=&amp;#39;--&amp;#39;, c=&amp;#39;black&amp;#39;)
plt.show()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://imrankhan17.github.io/pages/figs/secretary/fig3.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;img&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence , if we decide to quit on the optimal time to quit is try giving 37% exams and quit if the score is lower than the lower score you got before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so i was ready to give 8 exams and my score were [84,87,88,94,90,92]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37% of 8 = 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My score was improving after 3rd exam so i guess i was right to keep giving exams but the 5th exam my score went down i guess i should have quit then instead of giving one more exam. I lost another 3 month preparing for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:-by Kapil Khanal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do you have to wait more for the buses?</title>
      <link>/post/inspectionparadox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/inspectionparadox/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;average-for-group-vs-individual&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Average for group vs Individual&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;B&gt;Inspection Paradox&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/InspectionParadox_files/sajha.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buses and trains are supposed to arrive at constant intervals, but in practice some intervals are longer than others. This means the buses do not follow schedule exactly. There is always some randomness..With your luck, you might think you are more likely to arrive during a long interval. It turns out you are right: a random arrival is more likely to fall in a long interval because, well, it’s longer..!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s think of a scenario…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose a Bus service in your city says they pass a station every 10 minutes. This means you will assume that when you go to station randomly you would think that the average time is 5 minutes but more often you will be waiting longer than five minutes actually 10 minutes on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of this paradoxes is: Most of the school report there average class size. But if you, as a student that average is not accurate. Say, there are 4 classes of size 75,13,12,10. Then, the average colleges will report is &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\((75 + 13 +12 +10)/4 = 27.5\)&lt;/span&gt; but you as a prospective student, the average is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are more likely to be in room with 75 students &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(((75*75) + (13*13)+(12*12)+(10*10))/110 = 54.89\)&lt;/span&gt;. Hence, the average reporting is not for you. This kind of paradoxes happen everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generalize it in a more abstract way,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one case where the perspective of the individual and the group differs.For group, the average is what happens but as a individual the average will not make any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
